Preliminary Guide to the Treasurers Office records, 1903-1990 RG0008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Financial records, 1982-1990; RG0008 Series 12; 13.5 Linear feet
  - Burns Addition: Second BZA, Traffic Consultant, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center Addition: Square 75, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    BZA order 14261
  - BZA 14261: Court Case 88-264, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Burns Clinic: Final BZA Order, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Burns BZA 14265, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Volume 3
  - Burns BZA 14265, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Volume 2
  - Burns Clinic BZA, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    14265 Transcript
  - Burns BZA, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    14265
  - Second Half, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Regarding Tax
  - First Half Taxes, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 2nd Half, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Regarding Taxes
  - 1st Half, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Assessment Appeals, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Exemption Applications, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1925 F Street, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Regarding Assessment Appeals
  - Exemption Applications, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Income Expense, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Exemptions Requests, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Exemptions Requests, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Exemptions Requests, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exemptions Requests, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - FPL-161, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - FPL-161, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Assessments, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Proposed Property Assessment, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Association of Real Estate Officials, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Assessment File, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FP-161, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Burns Addition BZA, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Burns Addition Pre-BZA, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    14261 Volume 3
  - Burns Addition Pre-BZA, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    14261 Volume 2
  - Burns Addition Pre-BZA, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    14261 Volume 4
  - Burns Clinic Litigation, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Burns Addition Pre-BZA, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - 230 N Washington St #200, Rockville MD: Special Education, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - TQM Space, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 600 New Hampshire Ave NW, Suite 475: IPW West, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Institute for Law and Aging: 2011 Eye St NW, Suite 307 North, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 2011 Eye Street NW, Suite 400 North: Comptroller's Office North, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue: Taxes, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kenneth D Brooks: Chronology, 01/01/1987-03/31/1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kenneth D Brooks: Chronology, 04/01/1987-07/31/1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kenneth D Brooks: Chronology, 05/01/1986-06/30/1986 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Kenneth D Brooks: Chronology, 06/01/1985-07/31/1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 2100 Pennsylvania Ave NW: Payment Request, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 2013 Cunningham Drive: Tidewater Center, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    old C-56311-T03245
  - 515: 22nd Street, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    MFA Business Office, 6th Floor
  - Committee for Dulles: Economic Development Subcommittee, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Board of Trustees: Marketing Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1st Half, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 2nd Half, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Assessments, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1925 F Street, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Regarding Tax Appeal
  - Assessment Appeals, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tax Sale, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tax Sale, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tax Sale, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Tax Sale, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Nuisance Properties Tax Sale, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Tax Sale, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Tax Sale, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Tax Sale, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Square 43, Lot 841 and Sp 103, Lot 26
  - Tax Sale, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Square 43, Lot 841
  - Burns Permits, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Burns Clinic Tunnel Application, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Clinic Expansion Bridge and Tunnel, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Zoning Commission
  - Pedestrian Connection Lease, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Clinic Subdivision, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 1333 H Street NW, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Square 250, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sp 250: Elder, 05/1982-06/1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sp 250: IRS Ruling, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Development Square 250: Budget, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lot 11, Sp 250, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Hurston
  - Square 250: Construction, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Square 250: API Sub-Tenant, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Square 250: Design, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Square 250: Income/Expense, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Square 250: Partnership Agreement, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Square 250: Insurance, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Square 250: Old Leases, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Square 250: Real Estate Development, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Square 250: New York Life Sublease, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Square 250, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Square 250: Elder Proposal, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Square 250: Water and Sewer Availability, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Invoices, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Suite 210: 2020 K Street NW, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    National Law Center: Government contracts
  - Suite #710, 2021 K Street NW, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Suite 100, 45299 Research Place: Ashburn Virginia, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 2025 I Street NW: Suites 1018, 1019, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - 2025 I Street NW: Suites 632, 625, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - 600 New Hampshire Ave NW, Suite 480, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    ITSR
  - 1229 25th Street NW: BNA, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - 2445 M Street NW, Suite 275: BNA, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Health Care Science
  - 515 22nd Street NW, Suites #401, 402, 403, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    SR, PP, CE and SGBA
  - 2025 Eye Street NW, Suites #617-620, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    RRCEP
  - 2141 K Street NW, Suite 605, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - 2201 Virginia Ave NW, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Riverside Towers dormitory
  - 908 New Hampshire Ave, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Student Health Service
  - 1735 Jefferson Davis Highway, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Crystal Plaza, Virginia
  - 1844 Columbia Rd NW: Medical Center Clinic, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - 515 22nd Street NW: School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    Space B 5th Floor
  - 515 22nd Street NW,5th Floor: School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Suite 210, 2021 K Street, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Sponsored research projects, 1969-1984; RG0008 Series 13; 6 Linear feet
  This series contains files from various projects including NASA, NIH, Navy, D.C. Government, American Cancer Society, and the Ford Foundation. This material cover the dates 1969-84.
  Formerly ACC#67 and RG 8.1.
- Sponsored research projects, 1973-1984; RG0008 Series 14; 6 Linear feet
  This series contains sponsored research contract files including Jenny Moore Fund, Smithsonian, U.S. Office of Education, the Ford Foundation, and the Rockefeller Foundation. This material covers the dates 1973-84.
  Formerly ACC#81 and RG8.1
- Sponsored research projects, 1972-1984; RG0008 Series 15; 6 Linear feet
  This series contains sponsored research contract files. Some of these files relate to the U.S. Office of Education. These materials date from 1972-84.
  Formerly ACC#109 and RG 8.1
- Office files, 1820-2003; RG0008 Series 16; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains correspondence, receipts, brochures, proposals, reports, press releases, biographic information, a questionnaire, reports, memorandums, guides, and an invitation. They range in date from 1820 to 2003. The materials concern real estate transactions; student loans; services; planning; physical facilities; budgets; endowments; annual reports; the Fiscal Planning and Budgeting Committee, the Information Systems and Services (ISS); the Computer Information and Resource Center (CIRC); the Advisory Council on Academic Computing; the Center for Academic and Administrative Computing; Information Technology Services; and technology. Materials also concern Henry W. Herzog, formerly University Vice President and Treasurer.
  Formerly vertical files
- Certificates, 1921-1924; RG0008 Series 17; .25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains real estate appraisal certificates for George Washington University from 1921.
  - Real Estate Certificates for GW, 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    This folder contains five real estate appraisals made for the George Washington University. They date from 1921-24.
  - Correspondence concerning real estate certificates for GW, 06/22/1921-07/26/1921 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    This folder contains four pieces of correspondence relating to the real estate appraisals made for the George Washington University. They date from June 22- July 26, 1921.
  - Washington Real Estate Board appraisal of University property, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    This folder contains a list of the Washington Real Estate Board's appraisal of University Property. This list includes the location of buildings and their estimated values. This document dates to ca. 1921.
- Reports, photographs, memorabilia, circa 1920-2010; 1993-2010; Series 18; 4 Linear Feet
  - Framed photographs, circa 1990-2010; Series 18; 1 Linear Feet (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    This box contains framed photographs of GW campus scenes. The photographs formerly hung in the hallway of the Rice Hall offfice of the Executive Vice President and Treasurer. Subjects include:
    1. Students reading on a bench. 2. Men in front of a ribbon, balloons in the background. 3. Asian dancers in yellow costumes with red fans. 4. Volleyball game, blue seats in background, ball in upper left. 5. Man standing above construction site. 6. Boys in a decorated car, driving through the city to a game. 7. Students standing in front of a solar car. 8. 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue lit up at night. 9. Naval officer commissioning. 10. Fountain/garden area.
  - Framed photographs, circa 1990-2010; Series 18; 1 Linear Feet (Box 2)
    11. Graduates celebrating, May 1993. 12. Students set up living area in front of Professor's Gate. 13. Baseball: Base coach, runner & baseman action shot. 14. Basketball: GW vs. Mississippi State, two players at net. 15. GW Women's crew team racing (yellow boat). 16. Indian girl in red dress, blurry tulips in foreground. 17. GW Basketball player #22 shooting. 18. GW student golfing, purple flowered tree in background.
  - President's Annual Reports and Financial Reports, 1990-2010; Series 18; 1 Linear Feet (Box 3)
    This box contains GW Presidents' annual reports from 1990 to 2007 and financial reports from 2007 to 2010.
  - University publications and memorabilia, circa 1920-2010; 1990-2010; Series 18; 1 Linear Feet (Box 4)
    This box contains a sample of "buff and blue" cloth from the 1920s or 1930s, university publications, GW pins and decals, and presidential inaugural buttons.
- Office files, 1920-1991; 1970-1991; Series 19; 0.5 Linear Feet
  - Washington Research Library Consortium memos, 1990; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Washington Research Library Consortium memos, 1989; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Washington Research Library Consortium memos, 1989; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Research Library Consortium memos, 1989; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lisner Auditorium memos, 1965-1982; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sewall Portrait, 1969-1991; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - University Campus Plan, 1965-1972; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - University Center - General, 1964-1987; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charles E. Smith Center Usage and correspondence, circa 1970-1979; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles E. Smith Center Usage and correspondence, circa 1920-1979; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- John Cantini Campus Unrest files, 1969-1972; RG0008 Series 20 (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
  This series contains material related to campus unrest and subsequent disciplinary hearings circa 1969-1971.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series contains material related to student disciplinary records which are regulated by FERPA. This series is currently unprocessed and must be reviewed by an archivist before access can be granted. Please contact the archives for more information.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Records were discovered in basement of 2133 I Street NW in early 2015, when the building was being vacated, and were transferred to the archives by the Division of Operations.
- Charles E. Diehl zoning and property files, 1958-1976; RG0008 Series 21 (Box 4, Box 5)
  This series contains materials relating to zoning and property, particularly 1925 F. Street, Warwick Memorial, Washington Home for Foundlings, Eye Street Closure, WMATA underpinning and Square 40 circa 1958-1976.
- John Cantini Price Control files, Urban Law Institute, Workshops for Careers in the Arts, and Bader Gallery files, 1961-1971; RG0008 Series 22 (Box 6)
  This series contains John Cantini files relating to price control, the Urban Law Institute, Workshops for Careers in the Arts, and Bader Gallery.